Mphatso Lichapa

FULL-STACK WEB DEVELOPER

React | Javascript | Ruby | Rails

SUMMARY

lichapau@gmail.com | GitHub | LinkedIn | Twitter | AngelList

A full-stack developer with 2+ years of experience building scalable web applications for mid-sized companies. Actively building projects using a range of technologies and programming languages. Worked with developers from all over the globe through remote paired programming and mob programming. Good ability to solve problems with data structures and algorithms.

SKILLS

Front-End: JavaScript, React, Redux, jQuery, HTML5, CSS3

Back-End: Ruby, Rails, MySQL

Tools & Methods: Git, GitHub, Heroku, Netlify, Mobile/Responsive Development, RSpec, TDD, Chrome Dev Tools

Professional: Remote Pair-Programming, Teamwork, Mentoring

EXPERIENCE

HIGHLIGHTED PERSONAL PROJECTS

Remote

Full Stack Web Developer

March 2017, - Present

Math Magician — A single-page app that has a calculator and shows random quotes on a quote page.

Built with: JavaScript, HTML, CSS, React

Smashing Magazine Teardown — Breaking apart the website for a popular design magazine.

• Built with: HTML/CSS.

<u>Leaderboard</u> — Shows the scores of users stored on an API and users get to add/see the top scores.

• Built with: JavaScript, HTML and CSS.

MICROVERSE Remote

Mentor (Volunteer)

October 2021 – June 2022

- Mentored junior web developers, and provided 30% satisfaction in technical support through code reviews.
- Proposed improvements to code organisation and quality which also increase overall performance by 40%.
- I shared tips on maintaining motivation to maintain longevity in the program which resulted in 25% fewer dropouts among my mentees.

UNICAF UNIVERSITY

Lilongwe, Malawi

ICT Officer

November 2016 - March 2022

- Reduced system downtime by 70% with the introduction of hardware redundancies.
- Introduced an online asset management system to improve accountability and information sharing.
- Received Award of ICT Trainer for training 84 Employees and 350+ students.

EDUCATION

MICROVERSE

August 2020 - Present

Remote Full Stack Web Development Program, Full Time

- Committed 1300+ hours mastering algorithms, data structures, and full-stack development while simultaneously developing projects with Ruby, Rails, JavaScript, React, and Redux.
- Developed skills in remote pair programming using GitHub, industry-standard git-flow, and daily standups to communicate and collaborate with international remote developers.
- Improved effective ways of providing feedback in a team (Remote or In-person)

UNIVERSITY OF GREENWICH

July 2013 - June 2016

BSc (Honours), Business Information Technology

- Enterprise web software development
- Database Engineering